<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1"
	xmlns:md="eml://ecoinformatics.org/methods-2.1.1" 
	xmlns:proj="eml://ecoinformatics.org/project-2.1.1"
	xmlns:d="eml://ecoinformatics.org/dataset-2.1.1" 
	xmlns:res="eml://ecoinformatics.org/resource-2.1.1"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" 
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.0.2/eml.xsd"
	packageId="1970-01-01"
	system="catalogueoflife.org" 
	scope="system" 
	xml:lang="eng">

	<dataset>
		<alternateIdentifier>ISSN 1473-009X</alternateIdentifier>

		<title xml:lang="eng">Catalogue of Life</title>
		
		<creator>
			<organizationName>Species 2000 &amp; ITIS Catalogue of Life</organizationName>
			<address>
				<city>Leiden</city>
				<postalCode>2332 AA</postalCode>
				<country>NL</country>
			</address>
			<onlineUrl>http://www.catalogueoflife.org</onlineUrl>
		</creator>
		
		<metadataProvider>
			<organizationName>Species 2000 Secretariat</organizationName>
			<address>
				<city>Leiden</city>
      				<postalCode>2332 AA</postalCode>
				<country>NL</country>
			</address>
			<onlineUrl>http://www.sp2000.org/</onlineUrl>
		</metadataProvider>
		
		<associatedParty>
			<individualName>
				<surName>[authorsEditors]</surName>					
			</individualName>
			<role>editor</role>
		</associatedParty>		

		<pubDate>1970-01-01</pubDate>
		
		<language>eng</language>
		
		<abstract>
			<para>This release of the Catalogue of Life contains contributions from 171 databases with information on 1,858,893 species, 160,108 infraspecific taxa and also includes 1,710,428 synonyms and 422,542 common names covering the following groups:</para>
			<para>Viruses * Viruses and Subviral agents from ICTV_MSL
Bacteria and Archaea from BIOS
Chromista * Chromistan fungi from Species Fungorum
Protozoa * Major groups from ITIS Regional, * Ciliates from CilCat, * Polycystines from WoRMS Polycystina UPDATED!, * Protozoan fungi from Species Fungorum and Trichomycetes database * Slime moulds from Nomen.eumycetozoa.com
Fungi * Various taxa in whole or in part from CABI Bioservices databases (Species Fungorum, Phyllachorales, Rhytismatales, Saccharomycetes and Zygomycetes databases) and from three other databases covering Xylariaceae, Glomeromycota, Trichomycetes, Dothideomycetes * Lichens from LIAS
Plantae (Plants) * Mosses from MOST * Liverworts and hornworts from ELPT * Conifers from Conifer Database * Cycads and 6 flowering plant families from IOPI-GPC, and 99 families from WCSP * Plus individual flowering plants families from AnnonBase, Brassicaceae, ChenoBase, Droseraceae Database, EbenaBase, GCC, ILDIS, LecyPages, LHD, MELnet, RJB Geranium, Solanaceae Source, Umbellifers.
Animalia (Animals) * Marine groups from URMO, ITIS Global, Hexacorals, ETI WBD (Euphausiacea), WoRMS: WoRMS Asteroidea UPDATED!, WoRMS Bochusacea UPDATED!, WoRMS Brachiopoda UPDATED!, WoRMS Brachypoda UPDATED!, WoRMS Brachyura UPDATED!, WoRMS Bryozoa UPDATED!, WoRMS Cestoda UPDATED!, WoRMS Chaetognatha UPDATED!, WoRMS Cumacea UPDATED!, WoRMS Echinoidea UPDATED!, WoRMS Gastrotricha UPDATED!, WoRMS Gnathostomulida UPDATED!, WoRMS Holothuroidea UPDATED!, WoRMS Hydrozoa UPDATED!, WoRMS Isopoda UPDATED!, WoRMS Leptostraca UPDATED!, WoRMS Monogenea UPDATED!, WoRMS Mystacocarida UPDATED!, WoRMS Myxozoa UPDATED!, WoRMS Nemertea UPDATED!, WoRMS Oligochaeta UPDATED!, WoRMS Ophiuroidea UPDATED!, WoRMS Phoronida UPDATED!, WoRMS Placozoa UPDATED!, WoRMS Polychaeta UPDATED!, WoRMS Polycystina UPDATED!, WoRMS Porifera UPDATED!, WoRMS Priapulida UPDATED!, WoRMS Proseriata-Kalyptorhynchia UPDATED!, WoRMS Remipedia UPDATED!, WoRMS Scaphopoda UPDATED!, WoRMS Tanaidacea UPDATED!, WoRMS Tantulocarida UPDATED!, WoRMS Thermosbaenacea UPDATED!, WoRMS Trematoda UPDATED!, WoRMS Xenoturbellida UPDATED! * Rotifers, mayflies, freshwater hairworms, planarians from FADA databases: FADA Rotifera, FADA Ephemeroptera, FADA Nematomorpha &amp; FADA Turbellaria * Entoprocts, water bears from ITIS Global * Spiders, scorpions, ticks &amp; mites from SpidCat via ITIS, SalticidDB , ITIS Global, TicksBase, SpmWeb BdelloideaBase UPDATED! &amp; Mites GSDs: OlogamasidBase, PhytoseiidBase, RhodacaridBase &amp; TenuipalpidBase * Diplopods, centipedes, pauropods and symphylans from SysMyr UPDATED! &amp; ChiloBase * Dragonflies and damselflies from Odonata database * Stoneflies from PlecopteraSF * Cockroaches from BlattodeaSF * Praying mantids from MantodeaSF * Stick and leaf insects from PhasmidaSF * Grasshoppers, locusts, katydids and crickets from OrthopteraSF * Webspinners from EmbiopteraSF * Bark &amp; parasitic lices from PsocodeaSF * Some groups of true bugs from ScaleNet, FLOW, COOL, Psyllist, AphidSF , MBB, 3i Cicadellinae, 3i Typhlocybinae, MOWD &amp; CoreoideaSF* Twisted-wing parasites from Strepsiptera Database * Lacewings, antlions, owlflies, fishflies, dobsonflies &amp; snakeflies from LDL Neuropterida * Some beetle groups from the Scarabs UPDATED!, TITAN, WTaxa &amp; ITIS Global * Fleas from Parhost * Flies, mosquitoes, bots, midges and gnats from Systema Dipterorum, CCW &amp; CIPA * Butterflies and moths from LepIndex, GloBIS (GART), Tineidae NHM, World Gracillariidae * Bees &amp; wasps from ITIS Bees, Taxapad Ichneumonoidea, UCD, ZOBODAT Vespoidea &amp; HymIS Rhopalosomatidae* Molluscs from WoRMS Mollusca UPDATED!, FADA Bivalvia, MolluscaFW &amp; AFD (Pulmonata) * Fishes from FishBase * Reptiles from ReptileDB UPDATED! * Amphibians, birds and mammals from ITIS Global PLUS additional species of many groups from ITIS Regional, NZIB and CoL China</para>
		</abstract>
		
		<intellectualRights>
			<para>© 2020, Species 2000</para>
			<para>This online database is copyrighted by Species 2000 on behalf of the Catalogue of Life partners.</para>
			<para>Use of the content (such as the classification, synonymic species checklist, and scientific names) for publications and databases by individuals and organizations for not-for-profit usage is encouraged, on condition that full and precise credit is given at three levels on all occasions that records are shown. The three-part credit includes the complete work, the contributing database of the record, and the expert who provides taxonomic scrutiny of the individual record. For example, these might be as follows:
				
				1) Species 2000 &amp; ITIS Catalogue of Life: 2013 Annual Checklist,
				2) The full or short name of the contributing database, such as: Coreoidea Species File or CoreoideaSF,
				3) When provided, the latest taxonomic scrutiny field (specialist name &amp; date), such as Lohrmann V. &amp; Kroupa A.S., 05-Oct-2012 (from HymIS Rhopalosomatidae) or Barber-James H., Sartori M., Gattolliat J.L. &amp; Webb J., Feb-2013 (from FADA Ephemeroptera).
				This three-part credit can in many cases be kept brief by using a standard form and one or more logos as in the following example: "Species recognized by J. van Tol, Odonata database, ver. Dec 2011 in ". You may copy the Catalogue of Life logo from this example, on the DVD and web versions, for use in giving credit.
				
				If you wish to use the content on a public portal or webpage you are required to notify the Species 2000 Secretariat, both to request written permission and to assist with a check that the correct credits are given.
			</para>
			<para>Commercial Use				
				Use of this compilation or any of the databases contained within it by commercial organisations requires a written agreement from Species 2000 and ITIS. This applied when it is used commercially for external services, products or publications and when it is used to provide internal services within an organisation.
			</para>
			<!-- not sure if a disclaimer is IPR, but wont hurt to include it -->
			<para>Disclaimer				
				The Species 2000 &amp; ITIS Catalogue of Life editorial board cannot guarantee the accuracy or completeness of the information in this edition. Be aware that the Catalogue of Life is still incomplete and undoubtedly contains errors. Neither Species 2000 &amp; ITIS nor any contributing database can be made liable for any direct or indirect damage arising out of the use of Catalogue of Life.
			</para>
		</intellectualRights>
		
		<distribution scope="document">
			<online>
				<url function="information">http://www.catalogueoflife.org/</url>
			</online>
		</distribution>
		
		<coverage>
			<geographicCoverage>
				<geographicDescription>Global</geographicDescription>
			</geographicCoverage>
			
			<taxonomicCoverage>
				<generalTaxonomicCoverage>This release of the Catalogue of Life contains contributions from 171 databases with information on 1,858,893 species, 160,108 infraspecific taxa and also includes 1,710,428 synonyms and 422,542 common names.</generalTaxonomicCoverage>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Viruses</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Bacteria</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Archaea</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Chromista</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Protozoa</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Fungi</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Plantae</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
				<taxonomicClassification>
					<taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
					<taxonRankValue>Animalia</taxonRankValue>
				</taxonomicClassification>
			</taxonomicCoverage>			
		</coverage>
		
		<contact>
			<organizationName>Species 2000 Secretariat c/o Naturalis</organizationName>
			<address>
				<deliveryPoint>P.O. Box 9517</deliveryPoint>
				<city>Leiden</city>
				<postalCode>2300 RA</postalCode>
				<country>NL</country>
			</address>
			<phone>+31 71 7519362</phone>
			<electronicMailAddress>support@sp2000.org</electronicMailAddress>
		</contact>
		
	</dataset>
	
	<additionalMetadata>
		<metadata>
			<gbif>
				<dateStamp>2020-07-08T06:37:24+00:00</dateStamp>
				<citation identifier="ISSN 1473-009X">Species 2000 &amp; ITIS Catalogue of Life: 2020-04-16 Beta, Catalogue of Life</citation>
				<resourceLogoUrl>http://www.catalogueoflife.org/col/images/databases/Species_2000_Common_Names.gif</resourceLogoUrl>				
			</gbif>
		</metadata>
	</additionalMetadata>
</eml:eml>
